<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Mooloh's Dnd Menagerie</name>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
	</supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
		<li>
			<packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core,oskarPotocki.vanillaFactionsExpanded.core</packageId>
			<displayName>Vanilla Expanded Framework</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1854607105</steamWorkshopUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies> 

	<loadAfter>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core,oskarPotocki.vanillaFactionsExpanded.core</li>
    <li>spoonshortage.ADogSaidAnimalProsthetics</li>
	</loadAfter>
  <loadBefore>
    <li>seohyeon.OptimizationMeats</li>
  </loadBefore>
	<author>Mooloh</author>

	<packageId>mooloh.dndmenagerie</packageId>

	<description>  Adds over a dozen Dungeons and Dragons-inspired animals to RimWorld. 
  
  Given the antagonistic nature of most creatures in DnD, many of these animals only appear in raids from a unique faction, while other creatures are loyal allies that must be summoned, built, or tamed. Almost every animal has a non-vanilla ability, behavior, or item associated with it.

&lt;size=24&gt;Animal List&lt;/size&gt;

 - Golems: Constructed guardians that trade natural healing for extreme power. Requires a "Manual of Golems" item, a lot of materials, and a high construction skill to build one. There are three types of golems: flesh, stone, and steel, with flesh being the weakest, and steel being the strongest.

 - Animated Furniture: Reward animals that are created by using a "Scroll of Animate Objects" item on a chair, tool cabinet, or stool. Each type of animated furniture has a different behavior.

 - Flumph: A friendly, psychic jellyfish that can be tamed to produce a psychic-boosting drug.

 - Faerie Dragon: A small colorful dragon that can keep people happy with its euphoric breath.

 - Owlbear: A deadly apex predator with a huge appetite. Its damage and armor penetration are higher than you'd expect for a creature of its size. Can appear in the wild or in raids.

 - Displacer Beast: A magical feline that distorts light around its body. Boasts a high dodge chance, which is passed onto clothing made from its pelt. Can appear in the wild or in raids.

 - Basilisk: An eight-legged reptile that petrifies its prey. Can appear in the wild or in raids.

 - Medusa: A dangerous multi-headed reptile with a powerful petrification attack. Untameable and only appears in raids.

 - Gibbering Mouther: A blob of flesh that disorients nearby prey with magical babble. Can appear very rarely in the wild or in raids, and is untameable.

 - Beholder: A malevolent, otherworldly creature that shoots magical eye rays with 10 different effects. Rays that don't deal damage have a chance to pierce shield belts. Untameable and only appears in raids.

 - Spectator: A small cousin of beholders with 4 weaker eye ray attacks. Can appear in raids, or be summoned to join your colony by constructing a Spectator Effigy.

 - Rust Monster: A strange crustacean that eats rusted metals. Keep away from your metal stockpiles, armored warriors, and steel golems. Can appear in the wild, in raids, or even burrowing beneath your base.

 - Annihilator: A predatory cousin of rust monsters that disintegrates prey and consumes the resulting dust. Keep away from your... everything. Only appears in raids or manhunter events, and is nearly impossible to tame. 

&lt;size=24&gt;Other Features&lt;/size&gt;
    
 - Monster Faction: This faction is normally invisible like the mechanoid and insect factions, and it is the source of monster raids. These raids can consist of a variety of combinations of monsters to offer different threats and challenges. This faction can be disabled like other hidden factions with the Ideology DLC, or you can disable the raids directly in the mod's settings.
 
 - Rust monster infestations: This event is a cross between an insect infestation and an alpha-beaver migration. Passive rust monsters will spawn somewhere according to infestation spawning rules. Although they won't attack unless harmed, their metallic appetite might be a problem. This event can be disabled in the mod's settings.
 
 - Animal spawn controls: Individual spawn toggles for natural wild spawning (not raid spawning) can be found in the the "Vanilla Animals Expanded" mod's settings thanks to the Vanilla Expanded Framework's code for animal toggles. Spawn rates for animals in this mod can be modified through a slider in this mod's settings.

 - Ancient Notes: This item serves as a partial reward towards gaining the other rare items from this mod. They can be crafted into any of the three types of Manual of Golems items, or into a Scroll of Animation. Both ancient notes and the resulting items can appear as quest rewards or (expensive) trade goods.
 
 - Petrification: This effect can be applied by basilisks, medusae, and beholders. Mechanically it acts like a very slow-growing disease, with each petrifying hit adding severity. Patients require several days to build immunity, but good treatment can heavily stall the disease's progression outside of combat. Thankfully, 100% petrification isn't fatal - such victims are merely entombed alive in their body forever! The effect can be reverted using the antidote drug Antipet, which can either be harvested from Basilisks and Medusae, or crafted using a lot of neutroamine.
 
 - Resistance: Certain debilitating effects, like gibbering mouther babble, charm rays, and fear rays, will grant the victim a stacking resistance buff. This resistance decreases the likelihood that subsequent effects will take hold, and grants immunity at max stacks. 

 - Psy-kick: This is the drug that can be refined from Flumph "Ink". It boosts consciousness, psychic entropy recovery, and immediately grants a ton of psyfocus, but is comparable in addictiveness to go-juice. Obviously this is most useful if you have the Royalty DLC installed, but the drug's consciousness boost is still useful on its own.

&lt;size=24&gt;Mod Compatibility&lt;/size&gt;

  DnD Menagerie is compatible with the following mods:
  
  - A Dog Said... Animal Prosthetics: All organic animals are compatible with implants added by A Dog Said. That said, I don't add any new prosthetics, so some body parts - like displacer beast tentacles and entire spectator eyestalks - have no replacements. Also, inorganic and unstable creatures (golems, animated furniture, and gibbering mouthers) are ineligible for implants.
  
  - Giddy Up!: All sufficiently large, tameable animals besides Spectators can be ridden by default, and many animals have minor patches to make the mount/rider overlap look better. If Giddy Up! Battle Mounts is installed, animated dining chairs and stools gain stat bonuses while mounted.
  
  - Draftable Animals: Works without issue as far as I could tell.
  
  - Animal Search and Destroy: Tameable animals with multiple ranged attacks (currently just spectators) will choose randomly among toggled-on attacks, and can be set to only use a single attack type if needed.
  
  - Dungeons Core: Groups of animals from this mod are added as possible dungeon occupants, with a 25% of occurring per dungeon. Note that due to how Dungeons Core selects dungeons occupants, this 25% chance can't be toggled or turned off (yet). Also be warned: This threat spawns more creatures than others, and some of the animal spawn choices are very deadly. Have fun!
  
  This mod doesn't do much beyond adding animals, so I don't expect too many problems beyond possible issues between beholder rays and modded body shields. 

&lt;size=24&gt;Issues&lt;/size&gt;

  Balance is the main concern. I did some playtesting, but there are several new mechanics that can warp combat a bit. I'm very open to feedback regarding the resistance mechanic, shield-piercing rates for magical attacks, the general dps/tankiness of creatures, costs of rare items, and anything else. If you find a bug, please include a log if possible.
  
  The following is a list of known bugs:
  
  - Creatures targeting the victim of someone who just got thrown by a telekinesis ray will get confused when their target can't be found. They will properly select a new target after an error is logged. Fixing this would require checks in the combat AI code, which I don't want to do because of performance concerns for large lategame raids. 
  
  Other issues to be noted when they arise...
  
&lt;size=24&gt;Planned Features&lt;/size&gt;

  This mod is a passion project, and since I don't want to risk Wizards of the Coast coming after me for using DnD stuff, I have zero intention of ever monetizing this mod. That means that future development depends a lot on player interest. I have several other mod ideas that I'd like to work on next, but I'll certainly revisit this in the future if there's demand for it. I have a bunch of ideas for other DND creatures I'd like to put into RimWorld, and I'll happily take more ideas under consideration.
  
&lt;size=24&gt;FAQ&lt;/size&gt;

 - You call this a 'dungeons and DRAGONS' mod and you don't even have (full sized) dragons?! What gives?
   Off the top of my head I can think of at least three great mods that already add dragons into RimWorld. I wanted to add creatures from DND fantasy that I haven't already seen in my games before. That's not to say that none of these animals don't already exist in RimWorld mods, but I haven't seen them.
   
 - What about Liches? Those are pretty classic DND enemies too.
   I play too much RimWorld of Magic to feel like I can contribute anything with a new RimWorld Lich variety.
   
 - Beholders are supposed to have 10 eye ray effects - you're missing fear and charm rays.
   Those actually exist in my code, but after 3 different attempts at making fear and charm rays, I am still not satisfied with their behavior. There are too many buggy edge cases that I didn't want to introduce into the game. When these reach a stable state, I'll add them back in. This goes for spectator fear rays as well.

&lt;size=24&gt;Credits and Thanks&lt;/size&gt;

 - Code: Mooloh
 
 - Art: Erok
 
 - Big thanks to the many wonderful people on the RimWorld Discord's modding channel - especially Steve - who helped me learn, debug, and solve all sorts of issues that came up as I learned about modding.
 
 - Thanks to all the modders who listed their work on GitHub. I learned so much just from poking around the repos of my favorite mods, and I'm grateful that new modders stand on the shoulders of giants.

&lt;size=24&gt;Legal&lt;/size&gt;

 - MIT License: https://github.com/mlholland/MooDndMenagerie/blob/main/LICENSE
 
 - Source Code on Github: https://github.com/mlholland/MooDndMenagerie
 
 - I did a bunch of odd stuff behind the scenes in this mod. If you're a modder and you have any questions about how the code works, feel free to find me on Discord (mooloh#1554) and ask.

&lt;size=24&gt;Changelog&lt;/size&gt;

 - v1.1c: Added compatability for 4 other mods.
 - v1.0: Initial release
	</description>
</ModMetaData>